# Dilshani Karunarathna

No: 83/3, Temple Road, Malapalla, **Pannipitiya** 

**(**+94)-71058-9670

**⋈** dilshanik@eng.pdn.ac.lk

https://ddilshani.github.io/

www.linkedin.com/in/dilshanikarunarathna

https://github.com/DDilshani

#### Personal Statement

A motivated, dedicated, and capable research fellow with a solid research background, industry experience and a teaching portfolio. I am interested in developing a career which combines teaching and research while maintaining my interest in immersive technology.

### **Education**

### Bachelor of the Science of Engineering (Specialized in Computer Engineering)

Nov. 2016 - Sep. 2021

Faculty of Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka

First Class Honours

GPA: 3.7/4.0

Final Year GPA: 4.0/4.0

### G.C.E. Advanced Level Examination (Physical Science Stream)

Aug 2015

Ferguson High School Ratnapura, Sri Lanka

Z Score: 1.9553

Results: Combined Mathematics - A, Physics - B, Chemistry - A

## Work Experience

## Temporary Instructor - Department of Computer Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka

Sep 2021 - Present

- Contribute to the research works carried out in the faculty.
- Work as the Instructor In Charge of Computer Architecture and Compilers courses
- Conduct laboratory classes, and tutorial classes for the undergraduate students.
- Contribute to the projects carried out in the faculty as the Project Manager, Scrum master and Financial Assistant

#### Software Engineer Intern - Geveo Australasia Pvt (Ltd), Sri Lanka

Apr 2021 - Aug 2021

- Actively contributed to two ongoing projects with the primary focus on full-stack web development in an Agile environment.
- Developed new functionalities and features in line with the business requirements and functional specifications.
- Developed RESTful Web APIs
- Designed and implemented data models, stored procedures, and performed database manipulations.
- Involved in bug fixing on functionality and performance.
- Designed unit tests to ensure functionality.

### **Research Interests**

- Virtual Reality
- Mixed Reality

- Augmented Reality
- **Extended Reality**

- Cloud Computing
- Artificial Intelligence

th

# **Publications**

| Mixed Reality based Multi-Agent Robotics Framework for Artificial Swarm Intelligence Experiments Dilshani Karunarathna, Nuwan Jaliyagoda, Ganindu Jayalath, Isuru Nawinne, Roshan Ragel Robotics and Autonomous Systems Journal - Under Review  | 2022 |
|---|------|
| Mixed Reality based Multi-Agent Robotics Framework for Artificial Swarm Intelligence Experiments Dilshani Karunarathna, Nuwan Jaliyagoda, Isuru Nawinne, Roshan Ragel Technological Advances in Science, Medical and Engineering conferences - Abstract publication accepted                        | 2022 |
| Segmentation and significance of herniation measurement using Lumbar Intervertebral Discs from the Axial View Yuwin Siriwardhane, Dilshani Karunarathna, Imesh Ekanayake Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference (8 <sup>th</sup> International Multidisciplinary Engineering Research Conference) | 202  |
| Research Presentations  |      |

# Mixed Reality Environment for Swarm Robotics Simulations

Dilshani Karunarathna, Nuwan Jaliyagoda, Isuru Nawinne, Roshan Ragel.

Poster presented at: Peradeniya University Research Excellence Showcase 2022

July 2021

ESCaPe 2021 Online Project Symposium

Dilshani Karunarathna, Nuwan Jaliyagoda, Ganindu Jayalath

## **Research Projects**

| Dynamic Environment Setup using Swarm of Mobile Robots Introducing obstacle bots for a swarm robotic arena which is a part of a swarm robots platform project  | March 2022– Present              |
|--|----------------------------------|
| Self-Directed Learning Readiness and degree of stress among school and university students Identify aspects of learning patterns of students and to introduce an age appropriate education program to i (Self Directed Learning) amongst them.         | Oct 2021 - Present inculcate SDL |
| Projects   |                                  |
| <b>Zero Trash</b> A communication platform between users and garbage collectors to reduce waste collection costs and assist recycling process.   | 2020 st in the                   |
| <i>Traffic Sign Net</i> This system detects sign from the images to locate exactly traffic sign regions, and classifies each traffic signeresponding class.  | 2020<br>ign into a               |
| A GUI for Controlling and Supervising Multiple Robots Remotely  A GUI platform where a user can give commands which are to be followed by ground units in a remote local commands which are to be followed by ground units in a remote local commands. | 2019 ocation.                    |
| Pera Knowledge Hub  A web portal to upload and retrieve research papers, project reports, thesis done in the University of Perad   | 2019<br>leniya.                  |
| <b>Real-Time Vehicle Identification System</b> Detect the registration number of vehicles using camera images and automate the ticketing method at High booths.  | 2018<br>nway toll                |
| The Simple As Possible (SAP) – 1   | 2018                             |
| A computer with basic necessities using discrete logic ICs.  |                                  |

### **Awards**

| Best Research Paper under Big Data, Machine Learning, and Cloud Computing at Moratuwa Engineering | 2022 |
|---|------|
| Research Conference   |      |
| Best Research Presentation Award - ESCaPe 2021 Online Project Symposium                           | 2021 |
| • First place in Environment and Sustainability Category - ACES Hackathon                         | 2019 |
| • First place - PreXtreme (UoP)   | 2019 |
| • Country Rank: 21 Global Rank: 436 - IEEEXtreme 13.0   | 2019 |
| • Country Rank: 38 Global Rank: 499 - IEEEXtreme 12.0   | 2018 |
| • Fourth place - Let Me Hack v2.0   | 2020 |
| • Rank: 13 - ACES Coders v8.0   | 2019 |
| • Rank: 18 - ACES Coders v7.0   | 2018 |
| • Country Rank: 24 - Google Hash Code   | 2019 |
| • All Island Finalists - TADHACK  | 2018 |
| • Finalists - Sri Lanka Robotics Challenge  | 2018 |
| • Finalists - XbotiX Robotics Competition   | 2018 |
|   |      |
|   |      |

### **Certifications**

| • Introduction to Augmented Reality and AR Core, Google AR & VR - Credentials: F  | <u>YQ4SDG2596Z</u> 2022    |  |
|---|----------------------------|--|
| • Introduction to Big Data and Hadoop Course, Bangladesh Research and Education N | Tetwork (BdREN) - 2020     |  |
| Credentials: <u>fDLuDCf-DLE4-2132</u>   |                            |  |
| • Data Center Virtualization and Cloud Computing Infrastructure - Banglades       | sh Research and 2020       |  |
| Education Network (BdREN) - Credentials: fDLuDCf-DLE5-2344                        |                            |  |
| • AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud-Native, Amazon Web Services -                     | 2020                       |  |
| Credentials: <u>BT7ULEWL3M67</u>  |                            |  |
| • Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure, Google Cloud -         | 2020                       |  |
| Credentials: 2K6MB4MJ4KX4   |                            |  |
| • Server-side Development with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB, The Hong &            | Kong University of 2020    |  |
| Science and Technology - Credentials: 9AQJALJL45FB                                |                            |  |
| • Front-End Web Development with React, The Hong Kong University of Sci           | ence and Technology - 2020 |  |
| Credentials: 6D4K4CP9QKY8   |                            |  |
| • Neural Networks and Deep Learning, DeepLearning.AI - Credentials: <u>R5RN</u>   | <u>M43YJPFT2</u> 2020      |  |

## **Extracurricular Activities**

| • | Volunteer of Nenathambara Project   | 2021 - Present |
|---|---|----------------|
| • | Editor of Peradeniya Engineering Faculty Alumni Association (PEFAA) Newsletter 2022         | 2022           |
| • | Writer of Association of Computer Engineering Students (ACES) Outline 2019, the Newsletter  | 2019           |
| • | Member of the Association of Computer Engineering Students (ACES), University of Peradeniya | 2018-2021      |
| • | Member of the Ceylon Dramatic Society and Music Society, University of Peradeniya           | 2016-2021      |
| • | Member of the School Western Band, Ferguson High School                                     | 2007-2015      |
| • | Member of the School Choir, Ferguson High School  | 2014-2015      |

## **Professional Affiliations**

Student member of IEEE 2018-2021

## Referees

### Dr. Isuru Nawinne (Ph.D. UNSW)

Senior Lecturer, Department of Computer Engineering, University of Peradeniya. isurunawinne@eng.pdn.ac.lk (+94)-71849-5506

### Prof. Roshan Ragel (Ph.D. UNSW)

Senior Lecturer (Head of the Department), Department of Computer Engineering, University of Peradeniya. roshanr@eng.pdn.ac.lk (+94)-77385-7755